<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-23T19:12:57+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Kinyanjui Wangonya</title><subtitle>My online space</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Poetry</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/poetry-app/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Poetry" /><published>2018-08-06T22:10:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-08-06T22:10:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/poetry-app</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/poetry-app/">&lt;p&gt;A progressive web app utilising PoetryDb Api to explore poetry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HTML 5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CSS 3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bootstrap/Paperkit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PoetryDb Api&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Service Worker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wang0nya.github.io/poetry/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Check it out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>wang0nya</name></author><category term="project" /><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">A progressive web app utilising PoetryDb Api to explore poetry.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/poetry.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Fear</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fear/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fear" /><published>2018-07-30T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-07-30T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fear</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fear/">&lt;p&gt;It might seem simple, but have you ever thought about it? Fear is usually caused not by things that are actually happening, but by dangers we anticipate. 
As Seneca puts it,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“There are more things likely to frighten us than there are to crush us; we suffer more often in imagination than in reality.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is this important to know, you ask? Fear is important, no doubt. We would’nt survive without it. The kind of fear that gives us sense enough not jump off buildings is great. 
But there’s another kind of fear…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1319.The_War_of_Art&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The War of Art&lt;/a&gt;, Steven Pressfield talks about &lt;strong&gt;Resistance&lt;/strong&gt;: 
a universal force that acts against human creativity. Thinking about starting that blog but never had time to? Resistance. Want to be an artist but waiting for 
inspiration before you start? Resistance. Waiting for everything to fall into place (as if that will ever happen this side of heaven) so you can turn your 
passion into a career? Resi… you get it. If you’re a writer who doesn’t write, a painter who doesn’t paint, an entrepreneur who never starts a 
venture, then you know what Resistance is. Now, this is where things get interesting. Resistance is experienced as fear; the degree of fear equates to the strength of Resistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, we fear failing. Unbeknownst to us though, we also fear succeeding. We fear discovering that we are more than we think we are. More than our parents/children/teachers think we are. We fear that we actually possess the talent that our still, 
small voice tells us. That we actually have the guts, the perseverance, the capacity. We fear that we truly can steer our ship, plant our flag, reach our Promised Land. 
We fear this because, if it’s true, then we become estranged from all we know. We pass through a membrane. We become monsters and monstrous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problem with this kind of fear is, it does’nt manifest itself the same way normal fear does. It’s more subtle. Too subtle, I might add. You’ll not be shaking, your heart rate won’t increase and you’ll definitely not 
be saying to yourself, “I really hope I don’t succeed in this”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how does it manifest itself? There’s a couple of ways which are beyond the scope of a single blog post. I’ll just point out the most obvious: Procrastination. 
Procrastination is the most common manifestation of Resistance because it’s the easiest to rationalize. We don’t tell 
ourselves, “I’m never going to do it.” Instead we say, “I am going to do it; I’m just going to start tomorrow.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The fool, with all his other faults, has this also, he is &lt;strong&gt;always getting ready&lt;/strong&gt; to live.” -Seneca&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, we’ve established a few things so far. First, that fear is usually caused by perceived and anticipated dangers. Second, that we’re not talking about 
the usual kind of fear, but the fear that stops us from living the life we should be living, otherwise known as Resistance. Finally, that we don’t follow our passions because, 
a) we fear failing, and b) interestingly enough, we fear succeeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because we know that these fears are only anticipated, unless we can predict the future, who knows if they’ll actually happen? And if we can’t know, 
is it really worth fearing? It is likely that some troubles will befall us; but it if that trouble is not a present fact, does it make sense to run out to meet our suffering? 
We’ll suffer soon enough, so meanwhile, we should be looking forward to better things. If you’ve lived this life at all, you know how often 
the unexpected has happened, and how often the expected has never come to pass. There’s only two ways things could go, and there’s only one way to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back at my life right now, I realise that I’ve made so many bad choices, failed to do what I should be doing, simply because of fear, and most of what I feared never even happened. 
I could be writing more often if I didn’t always take so much time thinking if people will like what I put out or not. I’m sure I’m not alone. As much as we should always strive to put out quality 
content, really, so what if its not that good? What better way to learn than from your mistakes. Done is better than perfect. I think sometimes it’s best just not to care. 
If you enjoy what you do, go for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Most of us have two lives. The life we live, and the unlived
  life within us. Between the two stands Resistance.” -Steven Pressfield&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>wang0nya</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="life" /><category term="fear" /><category term="motivation" /><summary type="html">It might seem simple, but have you ever thought about it? Fear is usually caused not by things that are actually happening, but by dangers we anticipate. As Seneca puts it, “There are more things likely to frighten us than there are to crush us; we suffer more often in imagination than in reality.”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/blog/fear.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Plato’s Cave</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/platos-cave/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plato's Cave" /><published>2018-07-21T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-07-21T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/platos-cave</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/platos-cave/">&lt;p&gt;Now, I’m not a philosopher, not by a long shot. But I do read widely, and I came across an interesting allegory
Plato presents in his work &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/30289.The_Republic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Republic&lt;/a&gt;. 
It has come to be known as &lt;strong&gt;The allegory of the cave&lt;/strong&gt;, and goes something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;breaker&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are people (let’s call them prisoners) living in a cave. They have lived there since childhood shackled by the legs and neck and know nothing of the outside world.
Thus they stay in the same place so that there
is only one thing for them to look at: whatever they encounter in front of their faces. Because they are
shackled, they are unable to turn their heads around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you would expect, there are no windows in the cave so it is dump and dark. There is, however, a fire that casts its glow toward
them from behind them, being above and at some distance. Between the fire and the prisoners (i.e., behind their backs) there runs 
a walkway at a certain height. Occasionally, people pass through this walkway carrying all sorts of things - statues and other carvings 
made of stone or wood and many other artifacts that people have made. Shadows of these passing people and artifacts are cast upon the wall that these
prisoners face. Being unable to turn and look behind them, the prisoners perceive these shadows to be the reality and even name and classify them.
They see nothing else besides the shadows that are continually projected on the wall opposite them by the glow of the fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By chance, one of the prisoners is able to escape and find a way out of the cave into the open. Ever been asleep and had someone suddenly shine a light in
your eyes? The sunlight hurts his eyes and it takes time to adjust to the brightness. Once he is able to see clearly…
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/mog.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;
He sees that there are actually &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; things, and that the shadows are just mere reflections of those things. The shadows appeared much clearer 
to him because they were all he’d knew since childhood. Before, he had only seen shadows of people, animals, plants and artifacts.
Now he sees the real objects, and their shadows as cast by the light of the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Illuminated and enlightened, he observes the vastness and sublimeness of the universe. 
Previously he had been looking merely at phantoms; now he is nearer to the true nature of being.” -Plato&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prisoner returns to the cave to share his discovery but is no longer used to the darkness and has a hard time finding his way around the cave and seeing the shadows on the wall. The 
other prisoners tell him that it was a waste of time going to “the upper world”, and that it has made him stupid and blind, since he is now unable 
to comprehend what he knew so well before he left: the shadows. He seems to the others totally foolish, while he in turn is unimpressed by them. 
They refuse to listen to what he has to say, resist any attempts to get free, and even plot to kill him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/allegory.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;breaker&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plato says that the object of the allegory is to compare “the effect of education (an enlightening experience) and the lack of it on our nature”.
It shows that most people are not just comfortable in their ignorance, but hostile to anyone that points it out. All of us have been there. We think 
we &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; what we think we know, but is what we think we know to be reality really reality or are we like the prisoners, because of our environment, upbringing, education, religion, 
culture – our caves and shackles – just seeing shadows and taking them to be reality since its all we’ve ever seen, and all we &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; see?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many times do you argue with people trying to convince them of something contrary to what they’ve always known to be true? Yeah, you’re already picturing 
that guy or group of people to whom you were speaking to. But remember that time you were part of that group of stiff-necks and could’nt take what that other person was saying?
You may think you’re out of the cave but you’re just in another cave. The question is, who’s really out of every cave?﻿
How about always keeping an open mind? :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Don’t be in a hurry to condemn because he doesn’t do what you do or think as you think or as fast. 
There was a time when you didn’t know what you know today.” -Malcolm X&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;breaker&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/american-cave.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;What shapes your reality?&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;breaker&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>wang0nya</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="philosophy" /><category term="life" /><summary type="html">Now, I’m not a philosopher, not by a long shot. But I do read widely, and I came across an interesting allegory Plato presents in his work Republic. It has come to be known as The allegory of the cave, and goes something like this: There are people (let’s call them prisoners) living in a cave. They have lived there since childhood shackled by the legs and neck and know nothing of the outside world. Thus they stay in the same place so that there is only one thing for them to look at: whatever they encounter in front of their faces. Because they are shackled, they are unable to turn their heads around.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/blog/plato.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cars &amp;amp; Chrome</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/c-n-c/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cars &amp; Chrome" /><published>2018-07-15T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-07-15T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/c-n-c</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/c-n-c/">&lt;p&gt;Cars &amp;amp; Chrome club of Kenya formerly known as Carbs &amp;amp; Chrome club was formed in April 2018. The main purpose was to bring back the old car spirit in Kenya. Much attention has never been put on old cars. Through this forum, the spirit of brining back to life old cars is reborn again. The club seeks to bring together classic and vintage car owners, restorers (mechanics) and enthusiasts . The club set on hosting community based events such as charity events and also social event to form a strong cohesion among group members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HTML 5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CSS 3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wang0nya.github.io/cars-n-chrome/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Check it out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>wang0nya</name></author><category term="project" /><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">Cars &amp;amp; Chrome club of Kenya formerly known as Carbs &amp;amp; Chrome club was formed in April 2018. The main purpose was to bring back the old car spirit in Kenya. Much attention has never been put on old cars. Through this forum, the spirit of brining back to life old cars is reborn again. The club seeks to bring together classic and vintage car owners, restorers (mechanics) and enthusiasts . The club set on hosting community based events such as charity events and also social event to form a strong cohesion among group members.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/cars.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Currency Converter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/currency-converter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Currency Converter" /><published>2018-06-29T22:10:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-06-29T22:10:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/currency-converter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/currency-converter/">&lt;p&gt;Andela Learning Community (ALC) #7DaysofCodeChallenge front-end application that takes advantage of the functionalities FreeCurrencyConverter api provides. The application converts one currency to another while offline or online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PWA fully functional and installable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Service Worker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IndexedDb&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Html 5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CSS 3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JS (es6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wang0nya.github.io/Currency-Converter/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Check it out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>wang0nya</name></author><category term="project" /><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">Andela Learning Community (ALC) #7DaysofCodeChallenge front-end application that takes advantage of the functionalities FreeCurrencyConverter api provides. The application converts one currency to another while offline or online.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/CC.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Camper!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/camper/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Camper!" /><published>2018-03-16T22:10:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-03-16T22:10:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/camper</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/camper/">&lt;p&gt;Camper! is a website for tourists (local and foreign) to browse for suitable campsites. I got the idea to make it when following a Web Developer bootcamp course on Udemy. It’s made with Angular 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Angular 5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Express&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NodeJs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MongoDb&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Firebase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://camperproject.herokuapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Check it out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>wang0nya</name></author><category term="project" /><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">Camper! is a website for tourists (local and foreign) to browse for suitable campsites. I got the idea to make it when following a Web Developer bootcamp course on Udemy. It’s made with Angular 5.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/camper.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SpeakLife</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/speaklife/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SpeakLife" /><published>2018-01-26T22:10:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-01-26T22:10:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/speaklife</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/speaklife/">&lt;p&gt;A very simple website made with Wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wordpress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://speaklife.co.ke/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Check it out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>wang0nya</name></author><category term="project" /><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">A very simple website made with Wordpress.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/SL-mockup.png" /></entry></feed>